<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Excel on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/excel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Excel on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/excel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis in Excel - Part Two</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went over some useful Excel functions in the first of two parts about analysis in Excel. For part two I thought I’d go over some other tools available within Excel, including some examples of how to use them.
Conditional Formatting Conditional formatting allows you to highlight cells based on certain values or rules. Some examples of this includes highlighting duplicate values, or highlighting values over or under a specified value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis in Excel - Part One</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Last week I promised to post the first of two parts on using Excel for analysis. With the first post, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d list some useful functions in Excel, and provide some examples on how to use them. Please note that this list isn&amp;rsquo;t comprehensive - there are numerous other functions that can and should be learned to complement what is included here.
Look-up functions Look-up functions are used when you want to find a value that relates to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Excel</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</guid>
      <description>This week I thought I&amp;rsquo;d discuss using Excel for analysis. I also wanted to mention something I recently heard at work.
A co-worker of mine swears against using Excel for analysis. He will strive to use any other tool at his disposal.
After discussing his background in business intelligence - and history with tools like Tableau and PowerBI - I can kind of understand where he is coming from based on his current skillset.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>