<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Slam Winners</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/grand-slam-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/grand-slam-winners/</guid>
      <description>My focus for #TidyTuesday Week 15 was on getting better at exploratory analysis. This is a bit of a contrast to previous weeks where most of my effort has gone into data visualisation.
The Data Week 15&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Wikipedia. Inspiration for this week came from John Burn-Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s amazing article in the Financial Times.
The Analysis I decided to look at the top Grand Slam winners, but I broke this down by court type (grass, clay or hard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Bike Traffic</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday Week 14 was a good challenge for me. I wanted to focus on getting better at creating line charts with ggplot2, and I feel like I achieved that goal.
The Data Week 14&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about bike traffic in Seattle.
The Analysis SInce I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to get back up to speed with using R, I decided to keep it simple and focus on a) showing traffic over time, and b) showing which crossing registered the most traffic each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Pet Names</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</guid>
      <description>This is my post for #TidyTuesday Week 13, which looked at pet names in Seattle.
The Data Week 13&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about registered pets.
The Analysis Since this was a quick #TidyTuesday this week I decided to visualise the top ten pet names. I highlighted the most popular name in a different colour to help it stand out.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Policing Project Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</guid>
      <description>My second week taking part in #TidyTuesday! Let&amp;rsquo;s keep the ball rolling&amp;hellip;
The Data The data for week 12 was all about traffic stops made by US police officers, which comes from the Stanford Open Policing Project
Analysis I wanted to continue focusing on refreshing my ggplot2 skills this week, particularly around the use of using facet_wrap(). My approach to the analysis was to have a look at driver race in terms of number of traffic stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Game Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking part in #TidyTuesday, a weekly project focused on using tidyverse packages to clean, wrangle, tidy, and plot a new dataset. The big draw card for me is getting better at using R for analysis.
The Data The data for week 11 was all about board games, which comes from the Board Game Geek Database
Analysis I kept it very simple this week. This was mainly due to my R skills slipping over the previous year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>