<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Bike Traffic</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday Week 14 was a good challenge for me. I wanted to focus on getting better at creating line charts with ggplot2, and I feel like I achieved that goal.
The Data Week 14&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about bike traffic in Seattle.
The Analysis SInce I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to get back up to speed with using R, I decided to keep it simple and focus on a) showing traffic over time, and b) showing which crossing registered the most traffic each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Waste Appeared on UK Beaches in 2017?</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>Week 14 of #MakeoverMonday looked at the different types of waste found on UK beaches per 100m. The data comes from a 2017 by the Marine Conservation Society. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Clean layout with minimal colours Clear title and subtitle The icons help improve the design  What could be improved:  The scattered circles make it hard to compare each category What&amp;rsquo;s the bigger story behind this viz?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Pet Names</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</guid>
      <description>This is my post for #TidyTuesday Week 13, which looked at pet names in Seattle.
The Data Week 13&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about registered pets.
The Analysis Since this was a quick #TidyTuesday this week I decided to visualise the top ten pet names. I highlighted the most popular name in a different colour to help it stand out.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Different Generations Spend</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-13-2019-how-different-generations-spend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-13-2019-how-different-generations-spend/</guid>
      <description>Week 13 of #MakeoverMonday looked at how different generations are spending their income. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  The overall layout is simple and uncluttered Vivid colours help make each category stand out  What could be improved:  The legend could be moved to the top to help make reading the chart easier Each portion of each bar doesn&amp;rsquo;t start from the same place, so it tricky to compare across each age group (although the labels do help with this)  What I focused on:  I simplified the original visualisation by separating each age group and category into separate bar charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Policing Project Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</guid>
      <description>My second week taking part in #TidyTuesday! Let&amp;rsquo;s keep the ball rolling&amp;hellip;
The Data The data for week 12 was all about traffic stops made by US police officers, which comes from the Stanford Open Policing Project
Analysis I wanted to continue focusing on refreshing my ggplot2 skills this week, particularly around the use of using facet_wrap(). My approach to the analysis was to have a look at driver race in terms of number of traffic stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Reykjavik Index For Leadership</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-12-2019-the-reykjavik-index-for-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-12-2019-the-reykjavik-index-for-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Week 12 of #MakeoverMonday looked at the Reykjavik Index Index. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Simple colour scheme It is possible to figure see which countries are above average  What could be improved:  Being a radial chart, it&amp;rsquo;s circular nature makes it much harder to read than a bar chart The chart lacks context for what it is trying to show The G7 average gets a bit lost amongst the countries, despite being a different colour  What I focused on:  I wanted to show the data in a bar chart that had supporting commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Game Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking part in #TidyTuesday, a weekly project focused on using tidyverse packages to clean, wrangle, tidy, and plot a new dataset. The big draw card for me is getting better at using R for analysis.
The Data The data for week 11 was all about board games, which comes from the Board Game Geek Database
Analysis I kept it very simple this week. This was mainly due to my R skills slipping over the previous year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philadelphia&#39;s Housing Market</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-11-2019-philadelphia-s-housing-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-11-2019-philadelphia-s-housing-market/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally started taking part in the #MakeoverMonday challenge! Week 11 looked at real estate transfers in Philadelphia. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Clean area chart is easy to read Simple colour scheme Sorted bar chart  What could be improved:  The bar chart needs to be resized The map lacks detail The titles aren&amp;rsquo;t very helpful  What I focused on:  As it was my first week, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try and focus on clean design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Countries Contributed the most to Foreign Aid?</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/swd-challenge-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/swd-challenge-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>After a hiatus of a few months I&amp;rsquo;m back into taking part in the #SWDChallenge!
March&amp;rsquo;s challenge was a collaboration between Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic (Storytelling with Data) and Enrico Bertini (Data Stories podcast). The aim was to visualise a predefined data set and answer the question of &amp;lsquo;who donates?&amp;rsquo;.
The Data The dataset came from AidData
My Approach  Create a one page report that addressed the question Zero in on the highest donators and take a look at how they were contributing  Reflections What worked well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Motivation</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/12/finding-the-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/12/finding-the-motivation/</guid>
      <description>It has been a tough few months in the lead up to Christmas.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found my motivation to do, well, anything in data visualisation has severely waned. As a result, I took steps to try and reinvigorate my interest in what I was doing. For example, I started learning Tableau in late July, and shortly after began to post to things to my Tableau Public profile. I even started taking part in the #SWDchallenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearly A Year Later ...</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/10/nearly-a-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/10/nearly-a-year-later/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile.
Habits are interesting things. Good habits take awhile to form, but can be incredibly beneficial. I like forming good habits, but over the previous 11 months I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed how easy it is to break a habit - namely, blogging.
I started blogging back in November 2017 to get back into writing in a way that I actually enjoy, and to force myself to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation - The Big Book of Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/big-book-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/big-book-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I really like how the title says it all - it is indeed a very big book of dashboards.
I first came across the book in a post over at Storytelling with Data (one of my favourite sites for data visualisation inspiration). Since I pretty much trust anything that Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic endorses, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d buy the book.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this book at work for two to three months now, and I can honestly say that it has helped me more times than I can count when building dashboards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis in Excel - Part Two</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Last week I went over some useful Excel functions in the first of two parts about analysis in Excel. For part two I thought I’d go over some other tools available within Excel, including some examples of how to use them.
Conditional Formatting Conditional formatting allows you to highlight cells based on certain values or rules. Some examples of this includes highlighting duplicate values, or highlighting values over or under a specified value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When to Say No (and a bit of Self-Reflection)</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/when-to-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/when-to-say-no/</guid>
      <description>This week I’ve found myself in an all-too familiar trap. It started off with a client asking for a mock-up of a dashboard to be done ASAP. Now, I knew this task was looming on the horizon, but I had been putting it off mainly because I was helping the client with something else arguably more important.
Just to clarify, I had already talked to the client about putting off working on the dashboard due to the high priority task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis in Excel - Part One</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Last week I promised to post the first of two parts on using Excel for analysis. With the first post, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d list some useful functions in Excel, and provide some examples on how to use them. Please note that this list isn&amp;rsquo;t comprehensive - there are numerous other functions that can and should be learned to complement what is included here.
Look-up functions Look-up functions are used when you want to find a value that relates to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Excel</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</guid>
      <description>This week I thought I&amp;rsquo;d discuss using Excel for analysis. I also wanted to mention something I recently heard at work.
A co-worker of mine swears against using Excel for analysis. He will strive to use any other tool at his disposal.
After discussing his background in business intelligence - and history with tools like Tableau and PowerBI - I can kind of understand where he is coming from based on his current skillset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first step is taken</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/starting-somewhere-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2017/10/starting-somewhere-rmd/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
First and foremost, welcome to my blog.
This is something that I have wanted to do for a while now, but I always seemed to put it off. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to step into the wondrous world of blogging for a few reasons:
 I enjoy the process of writing, and I have recently missed this creative outlet
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading and learning from numerous analytics bloggers for the past three years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m a Senior Analyst based in Wellington, New Zealand. I have a strong interest in data visualisation and how to effectively communicate through a balance of effective design and thorough analysis.
My blog is a way for me to document tricks and tips about data visualisation, but it is also a way for me to document things I’ve learned along the way. My favourite tools to blog about are Tableau and R, but I will occasionally stray into blogging about Excel, Python and SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>