<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jbraggins.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>When to Say No (and a bit of Self-Reflection)</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/when-to-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/when-to-say-no/</guid>
      <description>This week I’ve found myself in an all-too familiar trap. It started off with a client asking for a mock-up of a dashboard to be done ASAP. Now, I knew this task was looming on the horizon, but I had been putting it off mainly because I was helping the client with something else arguably more important.
Just to clarify, I had already talked to the client about putting off working on the dashboard due to the high priority task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis in Excel - Part One</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/analysis-in-excel-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Last week I promised to post the first of two parts on using Excel for analysis. With the first post, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d list some useful functions in Excel, and provide some examples on how to use them. Please note that this list isn&amp;rsquo;t comprehensive - there are numerous other functions that can and should be learned to complement what is included here.
Look-up functions Look-up functions are used when you want to find a value that relates to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Defence of Excel</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/10/in-defence-of-excel/</guid>
      <description>This week I thought I&amp;rsquo;d discuss using Excel for analysis. I also wanted to mention something I recently heard at work.
A co-worker of mine swears against using Excel for analysis. He will strive to use any other tool at his disposal.
After discussing his background in business intelligence - and history with tools like Tableau and PowerBI - I can kind of understand where he is coming from based on his current skillset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The first step is taken</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/10/starting-somewhere-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/10/starting-somewhere-rmd/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
First and foremost, welcome to my blog.
This is something that I have wanted to do for a while now, but I always seemed to put it off. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to step into the wondrous world of blogging for a few reasons:
 I enjoy the process of writing, and I have recently missed this creative outlet
 I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading and learning from numerous analytics bloggers for the past three years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>