<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/categories/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/categories/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Economist Data Viz Mistakes</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/the-economist-data-viz-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/the-economist-data-viz-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>My focus for #TidyTuesday Week 16 was on trying to replicate a chart. For context, the idea was to explore the data behind some before and after charts from the Economist. Here are the charts I was looking at:
Instead of trying to make my own version of the better chart, I decided to try and figure out how to replicate some of the elements in it. Specifically: - Highlighting points in a scatterplot - Label the highlighted points, but to also add custom formatting to some of the labels only</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Word Count in Info We Trust</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/word-count-in-info-we-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/word-count-in-info-we-trust/</guid>
      <description>Week 16 of #MakeoverMonday was a collaboration with RJ Andrews, and looked at the most common words in his book Info We Trust.
What works well:  The most common word, data, stands out well People are used to seeing and interpreting word clouds  What could be improved:  Lack of a title or description Having words on different angles makes them hard to read Too many colours that don&amp;rsquo;t seem to serve a purpose  What I focused on:  I decided to show the top ten words per section in the book, which highlighted how common the word &amp;lsquo;data&amp;rsquo; is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grand Slam Winners</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/grand-slam-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/grand-slam-winners/</guid>
      <description>My focus for #TidyTuesday Week 15 was on getting better at exploratory analysis. This is a bit of a contrast to previous weeks where most of my effort has gone into data visualisation.
The Data Week 15&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Wikipedia. Inspiration for this week came from John Burn-Murdoch&amp;rsquo;s amazing article in the Financial Times.
The Analysis I decided to look at the top Grand Slam winners, but I broke this down by court type (grass, clay or hard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State Fiscal Condition 2016</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/state-fiscal-condition-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/state-fiscal-condition-2016/</guid>
      <description>Week 15 of #MakeoverMonday looked at ranking US states by fiscal condition. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Tidy design Good choice of colours Clear question in the title The top/bottom states are clearly stated  What could be improved:  It isn&amp;rsquo;t clear if things are improving or getting worse. Is this any different to the previous year? More information could be added in the form of text to help explain what is being shown here  What I focused on:  I struggled with this one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Longer and How to Emulate Your Heroes</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/live-longer-and-how-to-emulate-your-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/live-longer-and-how-to-emulate-your-heroes/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s #SWDChallenge was to find a visualisation you like and emulate it. I went with the &amp;lsquo;Live Long&amp;rsquo; chart by David McCandless of Information is Beautiful. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of David&amp;rsquo;s work. His visualisations are stunning. I even own two of his books - Information is Beautiful and Knowledge is Beautiful - which I love to flick through when I&amp;rsquo;m struggling for inspiration.
I decided to emulate the &amp;lsquo;Live Long&amp;rsquo; chart because a) I wanted to make an interactive version in Tableau, and b) I saw how I could apply my own style to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Bike Traffic</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday Week 14 was a good challenge for me. I wanted to focus on getting better at creating line charts with ggplot2, and I feel like I achieved that goal.
The Data Week 14&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about bike traffic in Seattle.
The Analysis SInce I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to get back up to speed with using R, I decided to keep it simple and focus on a) showing traffic over time, and b) showing which crossing registered the most traffic each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Waste Appeared on UK Beaches in 2017?</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>Week 14 of #MakeoverMonday looked at the different types of waste found on UK beaches per 100m. The data comes from a 2017 by the Marine Conservation Society. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Clean layout with minimal colours Clear title and subtitle The icons help improve the design  What could be improved:  The scattered circles make it hard to compare each category What&amp;rsquo;s the bigger story behind this viz?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Pet Names</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</guid>
      <description>This is my post for #TidyTuesday Week 13, which looked at pet names in Seattle.
The Data Week 13&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about registered pets.
The Analysis Since this was a quick #TidyTuesday this week I decided to visualise the top ten pet names. I highlighted the most popular name in a different colour to help it stand out.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Policing Project Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</guid>
      <description>My second week taking part in #TidyTuesday! Let&amp;rsquo;s keep the ball rolling&amp;hellip;
The Data The data for week 12 was all about traffic stops made by US police officers, which comes from the Stanford Open Policing Project
Analysis I wanted to continue focusing on refreshing my ggplot2 skills this week, particularly around the use of using facet_wrap(). My approach to the analysis was to have a look at driver race in terms of number of traffic stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Game Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking part in #TidyTuesday, a weekly project focused on using tidyverse packages to clean, wrangle, tidy, and plot a new dataset. The big draw card for me is getting better at using R for analysis.
The Data The data for week 11 was all about board games, which comes from the Board Game Geek Database
Analysis I kept it very simple this week. This was mainly due to my R skills slipping over the previous year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>