<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome and the Benefit of Self-Reflection</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/05/imposter-syndrome-and-the-benefit-of-self-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/05/imposter-syndrome-and-the-benefit-of-self-reflection/</guid>
      <description>The focus of this month&amp;rsquo;s #SWDChallenge was on artisanal data.
I found this challenge to be incredibly enjoyable. Why? Because I got to design a visualisation using data that I knew inside and out (since it was about my work history after all!). But hey, that was kinda the point, right?
I want to take a step back here though. I want to address why I used data about my work history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Motivation</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/12/finding-the-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/12/finding-the-motivation/</guid>
      <description>It has been a tough few months in the lead up to Christmas.
I&amp;rsquo;ve found my motivation to do, well, anything in data visualisation has severely waned. As a result, I took steps to try and reinvigorate my interest in what I was doing. For example, I started learning Tableau in late July, and shortly after began to post to things to my Tableau Public profile. I even started taking part in the #SWDchallenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nearly A Year Later ...</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/10/nearly-a-year-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2018/10/nearly-a-year-later/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! It&amp;rsquo;s been awhile.
Habits are interesting things. Good habits take awhile to form, but can be incredibly beneficial. I like forming good habits, but over the previous 11 months I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed how easy it is to break a habit - namely, blogging.
I started blogging back in November 2017 to get back into writing in a way that I actually enjoy, and to force myself to write about what I&amp;rsquo;m learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>