<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Visualisation on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/categories/data-visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Visualisation on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jbraggins.netlify.com/categories/data-visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Week 12 2019 - Stanford Policing Project Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-12-2019-stanford-policing-project-analysis/</guid>
      <description>My second week taking part in #TidyTuesday! Let&amp;rsquo;s keep the ball rolling&amp;hellip;
The Data The data for week 12 was all about traffic stops made by US police officers, which comes from the Stanford Open Policing Project
Analysis I wanted to continue focusing on refreshing my ggplot2 skills this week, particularly around the use of using facet_wrap(). My approach to the analysis was to have a look at driver race in terms of number of traffic stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makeover Monday Week 12 2019 - The Reykjavik Index For Leadership</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-12-2019-the-reykjavik-index-for-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-12-2019-the-reykjavik-index-for-leadership/</guid>
      <description>Week 12 of #Makeover Monday looked at the Reykjavik Index Index. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Simple colour scheme It is possible to figure see which countries are above average  What could be improved:  Being a radial chart, it&amp;rsquo;s circular nature makes it much harder to read than a bar chart The chart lacks context for what it is trying to show The G7 average gets a bit lost amongst the countries, despite being a different colour  What I focused on  I wanted to show the data in a bar chart that had supporting commentary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makeover Monday Week 11 2019 - Philadelphia&#39;s Housing Market</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-11-2019-philadelphia-s-housing-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-11-2019-philadelphia-s-housing-market/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally started taking part in the #Makeover Monday challenge! Week 11 looked at real estate transfers in Philadelphia. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Clean area chart is easy to read Simple colour scheme Sorted bar chart  What could be improved:  The bar chart needs to be resized The map lacks detail The titles aren&amp;rsquo;t very helpful  What I focused on  As it was my first week, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d try and focus on clean design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWDChallenge March 2019 - Which Countries Contributed the most to Foreign Aid?</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/swd-challenge-march-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/swd-challenge-march-2019/</guid>
      <description>After a hiatus of a few months I&amp;rsquo;m back into taking part in the #SWDChallenge!
March&amp;rsquo;s challenge was a collaboration between Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic (Storytelling with Data) and Enrico Bertini (Data Stories podcast). The aim was to visualise a predefined data set and answer the question of &amp;lsquo;who donates?&amp;rsquo;.
The Data The dataset came from AidData
My Approach  Create a one page report that addressed the question Zero in on the highest donators and take a look at how they were contributing  Reflections What worked well?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Week 11 2019 - Board Game Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking part in #TidyTuesday, a weekly project focused on using tidyverse packages to clean, wrangle, tidy, and plot a new dataset. The big draw card for me is getting better at using R for analysis.
The Data The data for week 11 was all about board games, which comes from the Board Game Geek Database
Analysis I kept it very simple this week. This was mainly due to my R skills slipping over the previous year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Recommendation - The Big Book of Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/big-book-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jbraggins.netlify.com/2017/11/big-book-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I really like how the title says it all - it is indeed a very big book of dashboards.
I first came across the book in a post over at Storytelling with Data (one of my favourite sites for data visualisation inspiration). Since I pretty much trust anything that Cole Nussbaumer Knaflic endorses, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d buy the book.
I wasn&amp;rsquo;t disappointed.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using this book at work for two to three months now, and I can honestly say that it has helped me more times than I can count when building dashboards.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>