<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis on Jared Braggins</title>
    <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis on Jared Braggins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jaredbraggins.com/tags/analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Longer and How to Emulate Your Heroes</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/live-longer-and-how-to-emulate-your-heroes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/live-longer-and-how-to-emulate-your-heroes/</guid>
      <description>This month&amp;rsquo;s #SWDChallenge was to find to a visualisation you like and emulate it. I went with the &amp;lsquo;Live Long&amp;rsquo; chart by David McCandless of Information is Beautiful. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of David&amp;rsquo;s work. The design choices he applies to his charts is stunning. I even own two of his books - Information is Beautiful and Knowledge is Beautiful - which I love to flick through when I&amp;rsquo;m struggling for inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Bike Traffic</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/tidy-tuesday-week-14-seattle-bike-traffic/</guid>
      <description>#TidyTuesday Week 14 was a good challenge for me. I wanted to focus on getting better at creating line charts with ggplot2, and I feel like I achieved that goal.
The Data Week 14&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about bike traffic in Seattle.
The Analysis SInce I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to get back up to speed with using R, I decided to keep it simple and focus on a) showing traffic over time, and b) showing which crossing registered the most traffic each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Kind of Waste Appeared on UK Beaches in 2017?</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/04/makeover-monday-week-14-2019-what-kind-of-waste-appeared-on-uk-beaches-in-2017/</guid>
      <description>Week 14 of #MakeoverMonday looked at the different types of waste found on UK beaches per 100m. The data comes from a 2017 by the Marine Conservation Society. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  Clean layout with minimal colours Clear title and subtitle The icons help improve the design  What could be improved:  The scattered circles make it hard to compare each category What&amp;rsquo;s the bigger story behind this viz?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seattle Pet Names</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidytuesday-week-13-2019-seattle-pet-names/</guid>
      <description>This is my post for #TidyTuesday Week 13, which looked at pet names in Seattle.
The Data Week 13&amp;rsquo;s data comes from Seattle&amp;rsquo;s open data portal and contains information about registered pets.
The Analysis Since this was a quick #TidyTuesday this week I decided to visualise the top ten pet names. I highlighted the most popular name in a different colour to help it stand out.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the code:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Different Generations Spend</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-13-2019-how-different-generations-spend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/makeover-monday-week-13-2019-how-different-generations-spend/</guid>
      <description>Week 13 of #MakeoverMonday looked at how different generations are spending their income. Here&amp;rsquo;s the original visualisation:
What works well:  The overall layout is simple and uncluttered Vivid colours help make each category stand out  What could be improved:  The legend could be moved to the top to help make reading the chart easier Each portion of each bar doesn&amp;rsquo;t start from the same place, so it tricky to compare across each age group (although the labels do help with this)  What I focused on:  I simplified the original visualisation by separating each age group and category into separate bar charts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Board Game Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jaredbraggins.com/2019/03/tidy-tuesday-week-11-2019-board-game-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started taking part in #TidyTuesday, a weekly project focused on using tidyverse packages to clean, wrangle, tidy, and plot a new dataset. The big draw card for me is getting better at using R for analysis.
The Data The data for week 11 was all about board games, which comes from the Board Game Geek Database
Analysis I kept it very simple this week. This was mainly due to my R skills slipping over the previous year.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>